Edmir Demaj Junior Full Stack Software Developer

Dublin, Ireland | +353 87 367 9307 | edmir_demaj@yahoo.com GitHub | Linkedin | Portfolio

Summary:

I am a Junior Full Stack Software Developer with a passion for building practical software and web applications with an excellent user experience. With knowledge in Frontend and currently learning Backend Development, I am skilled in leading technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, and Python. My background as a civil engineer has also helped me develop strong problem-solving abilities, which I effectively apply to software programming. My eagerness to learn new things will eventually position me at the forefront of IT professionals.

Education:

August 2022–Present Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland

September 2015–July 2016 Master of Engineering - MEng, Civil Engineering

Polytechnic University of Tirana - Tirana, Albania

September 2011–July 2014 Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Civil Engineering

Polytechnic University of Tirana - Tirana, Albania

Technical Skills:

• Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python

• Frameworks: **Bootstrap**

• Version Control: Git, GitHub

• Tools: Figma, VSCode, GitPod, LucidChart

Soft Skills:

- Excellent Communication
- Attention to details
- Problem-solving
- Teamwork

<u>Portfolio Projects:</u>

- 1. **Portfolio:** A website showcasing my skills and projects to recruiters and potential employers. Built with HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, and Bootstrap framework. View on GitHub: https://github.com/Edmir-Demaj/portfolio-Edmir-Demaj
- 2. Welcome to Albania: A simple static website presenting nature and promoting Albania as a country. Built with HTML5 and CSS3 as well as used Figma to create wireframes. View on GitHub: https://github.com/Edmir-Demaj/welcome-to-albania
- **3. Quiz Game:** A web application designed for users to test their knowledge with a variety of quiz questions. Built with HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript. View on <u>GitHub: https://github.com/Edmir-Demai/quiz-game.</u>
- 4. **Quality of Life Index:** A command line web app providing users with the QLI for different countries in the world. Built with Python and some Python libraries. View on <u>GitHub: https://github.com/Edmir-Demai/quality-of-life-index</u>

Work Experience:

Business Co-Owner, Giulio's Take Away - Drogheda, Ireland (June 2021-October 2022)

- Organized daily tasks for staff to provide high-quality customer service
- Managed and prepared paperworks as well as various reports

Customer Service Staff, Macari's Limited - Dublin, Ireland (March 2019–June 2021)

- Provided excellent and friendly service to customers
- Worked in a team environment

Relocated to Dublin, Ireland from Shkoder, Albania (January 2018–February 2019)

Site Engineer, A.K. Sh.p.k. - Tirana, Albania (*March* 2017–*December* 2017)

- Implemented construction projects on-site and prepared daily/weekly reports
- Designed with AutoCAD software
- Joined team meetings to assist with problem-solving

Water Engineer, Ujesjelles Fshat Sh.a - Shkoder, Albania (October 2016 – February 2017)

- Examined technical problems in the water supply system
- Made hydraulic calculations and assisted in the design of projects
- Instruct technicians and interpret technical designs for them on site

Interests/Additional Information:

- Participated in Code Institute January 2023 Hackathon: <u>GitHub/HelpSavvy Financial</u> Designed and created wireframes and developed a budget page using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript in this collaborative project
- Participated in Code Institute February 2023 Hackathon: <u>GitHub/NGO Directory</u> Held a Scrum role, created wireframes and developed a contact page in this collaborative project, where we won 3rd place!
- Enjoy listening to IT & Technology podcasts on Spotify
- Enjoys watching documentaries about new technologies and the future of tech in the world
- Enjoys surfing and hiking in nature, where brilliant ideas often come to mind
- Fluent in English, proficient in Italian, and a native Albanian speaker